个人收藏版=2013/14年整理
影片仅供个人收藏欣赏==不作为任何商业及其他用途==集网络资源个人整理/封装
哥们你要急死我呀?  不迟到会死啊?
Hurry up, dude! You're so late!
还没给钱啊?
I haven't paid yet.
赶紧!
Hurry up!
这个男人给你找来了
I found the man you want.
解决你很大的困难!
Your problem is solved!
晚上去我家喝点红酒?
Have red wine at my place tonight.
你也这么直接呀?
How direct!
不是都这样吗?  公牛追求母牛
Just like a cock chasing a hen, no?
你才是牲口呢!
You're the beast, not me!
哎 ... 同学们! 咱们开始吧!
Hey, everybody! Let's start!
你! 赶紧脱衣服吧!
You! Take off your clothes.
过来呀
Come here.
有没有搞错!
You kidding?
你自已泡妞把我当牺牲品
You're sacrificing me for the girl?
谁都知道来画室当模特儿要脱衣服的
Everyone knows a model has to strip.
这不是傻子吗?
You think I'm an idiot?
傻子没事!
No!
反正他们只关心你的大胸和大腿
They only care about your chest and legs.
冷呀! 能少脱就少脱!
It's cold.
脱上面就可以? !
Can l take off my top only?
扛着点!
Hang in there!
设想到荒村的作者竟然这么年青!
I didn't know THE VILLAGE's author is so young!
荒村是真名还是假名啊
Is the Village the name of a real village?
对呀! 地图上为什么找不到?
Yeah! Why can't we find it on the map?
它有没有改过名字呀?
Is the name altered?
你写的荒村那么神秘
Your tale is so mysterious!
我们到底怎么去呢
How do we get there?
喂! 我们还没说完呢!
Hey! We're not done yet!
你也太没礼貌了吧!
How rude of you!
你是不是瞧不起我们啊?
Are you snubbing us?
对不起! 是我没礼貌!
Sorry! It's rude of me!
但我不姓喂  我姓郭名径
But my name isn't Hey! lt's Gene.
不好意思!
Sorry!
是我们对不起你才是! 我们太激动了!
Please excuse us! We're being too excited!
我叫霍强  这是我女朋友韩小枫
I'm John. She's my girlfriend Fanny.
这是我好哥们苏天平  这女的是春雨
He's our pal Timmy. And she's Rain.
我们都是你忠实的读者!
We're all your loyal readers!
觉得你写的那种神秘力量很吸引人
We dig the mysterious force you describe.
对啊! 对啊!
Yes!
只有真诚相爱的人进了荒村
Only people truly in love...
才会受到鬼魂的祝福
will be blessed by Rouge in the Village.
但是虚情假意的
The hypocritical...
就会被胭脂的鬼魂盯上
shall be possessed by her spirit...
把他们整死! 是不是呀?
till they die! ls that right?
不过古代的胭脂 ...
How can an ancient spirit...
怎么能判断现代人的爱情?
judge modern love?
这是小事  关键是它浪漫!
What really matters is romance!
看你跟你你的爱人是不是真诚相爱!
She can tell whether you're truly in love!
没有荒村!
The Village doesn't exist!
荒村是我虚构出来的!
I made it up!
作家! 不撒谎怎么叫作家!
I'm an author! All authors are liars!
你刚才也是在撒谎吧?
Were you lying just now?
我刚才 ...
Just now...
就看到胭脂站在你的身后
I saw Rouge standing behind you.
你写过
You've written before...
胭脂会在撒谎的人身后出现!
Rouge will appear behind a liar!
我刚刚就看到胭脂站在你的身后笑!
I saw Rouge laughing behind you!
好啦
OK!
别自已吓自已
Stop scaring yourselves.
荒村我是去过
I've been to the Village...
但从来就没有胭脂!
but there's no Rouge.
那荒村到底在哪啊?
So where's the Village?
你别担心  我们都不怕胭脂的传说!
It's OK. We aren't scared of the legend!
我们己经决定年底结婚
We've decided to get married end of this year.
他们俩是青梅竹马
They've been dating since they're little.
没有胭脂!
There's no Rouge!
我也不会告诉你它在那!
And I won't tell you where it is!
再说爱情不是游戏  不能测试
Love is not a game. You can't test it.
那当初你为什么又要去呢?
Why did you go there in the first place?
只有你可以去探险  其他人就不行!
Only you could explore but nobody else can!
原来你只是个爱炫耀  又自私的作家
You're just a flaunting, selfish author.
对  我是自私的!
Yes, I'm selfish!
对不起  我可以走了吧?
Sorry, can I go now?
郭径  郭径
Gene, Gene!
你怎么弄到的?
How did you get it?
当然是偷的! 难道是郭径自已给我的?
I stole it! You think Gene would give it to me?
好个粉丝啊!
What a fan!
去不了荒村  偷张照片就满足了
If we can't go there, a pic is good enough.
准备好了吗?
Are you ready?
荒村
The Village.
什么荒村呀?
What do you mean "the Village"?
嗨  孙子!
Hey, Sun Tzu!
你才孙子! 我叫孙子楚!
My name is Tru Sun! Not Sun Tzu!
你帮我问一下
Can you ask for me...
有没有人在画室里面捡到我的东西呀?
if they found my thing in the atelier?
没有呀!
They didn't!
你都脱光了! 还能丢什么东西呀?
You were nude! What could you have dropped?
真的!
Really!
那 ... 算了  没事!
Then...forget it!
你太自以为是  根本不配当作家!
You're too egoistic to be an author!
你只是个骗子
You're only a liar.
你不应该写荒村这本书
You shouldn't have written THE VILLAGE.
更不该描述荒村!
You shouldn't have described it!
你己经种下祸根
You've opened the Pandora's Box!
外人会因为你进入荒村而受伤
Thanks to you, others will get hurt entering the Village.
说你是骗子
I call you a liar...
因为你犯了三个很离谱的错误!
because you've made three grave mistakes.
第一
First,
胭脂的鬼魂不会在人身后出现
Rouge doesn't appear behind a person.
她永远会在天花板上偷看你
She always peeps at you from the ceiling.
发现了吗?
Did you notice it?
对  我是骗子!
Yes, I'm a liar!
有哪个作家不是骗子呢?
Which author is not a liar?
我又不是写日记
I'm not writing a diary.
作家都会加上自已的幻想
All authors inject their own imagination.
我出书又怎么样?
So what if l published the book?
外人不可能因为我的描述而进入荒村
Nobody can enter the Village because of my description.
因为我藏了个秘密
I've hidden the secret.
你没察觉吗?
Haven't you noticed it?
你到底是谁?
Who are you?
你是谁呀?
荒村是个没有时间的村子
The Village is ageless.
大宅坐落于荒村
Inside the village there's a mansion...
但村民从来不会走进大宅
but villagers never go in...
因为一个古老的傅说 :
because of a legend.
明朝嘉靖年间
During the sixteenth century,
荒村大宅住了一对姓欧阳的夫妇
a couple named Ouyang lived in the mansion.
丈夫无故生病
The husband got ill...
最后死亡
suddenly and died.
他的妻子胭脂曾经跟丈夫起誓
His wife Rouge had promised him...
会一生世陪在他身边
she would stay with him forever.
胭脂信守诺言
Rouge kept her promise...
七天六夜陪在丈夫身边
and stayed by his side for 7 days and 6 nights.
结果丈夫奇迹地酲来
In the end, the husband miraculously woke up...
胭脂喜极而泣
Rouge was so elated...
告知众人奇迹出现了
she told the whole village.
可村民觉得她丈夫是鬼
But they believed her husband was a ghost...
还在大宅内把他活活烧死!
and burned him to death inside the mansion.
胭脂为了爱情
Because of love...
也引火自焚!
Rouge set herself on fire as well.
从此
From then on,
大宅开始闹鬼
the mansion has become haunted.
宅人一一死去
Anyone who stayed there died one by one.
大伯! 你们好!
Mister! How are you?
大伯!
Mister!
那么晚还待在外面?
Staying out so late?
哎! 你们是从城里来的吧?
You guys are from the city?
对! 我们是从城里来 的!
Yes, we're from Beijing.
北区你去过吗?
You've been there?
设有  不过打算明年春天就去!
No, but l plan on going in spring next year.
你们那儿工作好找吗?
Is it easy to find a job there?
还行吧! 不过我们几个都是学生!
It's OK! But we're students.
学生来这儿斡嘛?
What are students doing here?
你听过荒村大宅吗?
You heard of the mansion in the Village?
那有什么大宅啊!
What mansion?
我们这儿就几个破房子!
We only have run-down houses!
不可能吧!
That's not possible!
是这样  你这儿有住的地方吗?
Where can we find lodging here?
这里不是旅游区
This isn't a tourist area.
都这么晚了  就住我家吧!
It's so late. You can stay at my place.
顺便你们再给我讲讲城里边的事
You can tell me more about Beijing.
不过  我要警告你们
But I have to warn you...
晚上不要出来乱跑!
not to run around at night!
特别是听到什么奇怪的声音
Especially when you hear strange noises,
一定要待在屋子里!
you gotta stay indoors!
我叫胭脂
My name is Rouge.
你以为世间真有秘密吗?
You think secrets really exist in this world?
秘密能不被打开吗?
Can secrets remain unrevealed?
打开荒村入口的秘密
Once the entrance to the Village is exposed,
就如明月赶走黑暗
nature will become unprotected...
大自然的守卫飘走!
like darkness being dispelled by moonlight,
秘密便瞬间显现
and the secret will be unveiled instantly.
根本无法掩藏
There's no way to hide it.
这世界上
Only true love is...
只有真爱是不能被预知跟破解的!
undecipherable.
至于你个人的秘密
As for your personal secret,
你住在新四西路  以为没有人知道吗?
you think nobody knows you live on Xin Si Xi Lu?
你写的一切将危害他人
Your writings are maleficent.
你第二个错误
Your second mistake...
是不该吃着拉面看这封电邮!
is to eat noodles while reading this e-mail!
你真的是胭脂吗?
Are you really Rouge?
如果你真的是胭脂  我只能说对不起
If you are really Rouge, all I can say is sorry.
我不是你的丈夫
I'm not your husband,
而是活活烧死你的愚昧村民
but the stupid villagers who burnt him to death.
但我不认为你是胭脂!
But I don't think you are Rouge!
如果你要跟我玩猫捉老鼠的游戏?
You want to play cat-and-mouse with me?
我乐于奉陪!
Go ahead!
你一直指责我危害其他人
You keep saying that l'm maleficent.
到底为什么?
But why?
你说有人
You're saying someone...
看着你一边吃拉面一边看电邮  是吧?
saw you eating noodles while reading e-mails?
很奇怪!
That's weird!
怎么了?  是不是又有新电邮?
What happened? New e-mails?
我们这几天的通讯记录都没了!
Our chat history is all gone!
连备份都没了!
All saved memories are gone!
兄弟  你能不能肯定是这两天的事啊?
You sure it happened in the last two days?
你没梦游吧?
You didn't sleepwalk?
你听说过这种电脑高手吗?
Have you heard of those computer hackers?
不肯定
I'm not sure.
不过我觉得他不是什么电脑高手!
But I don't think that's a hacker!
你看!
Look!
从外面任何一个角度都不可能看到你
Nobody can see you from whatever angles...
在这儿一边吃拉面  一边看电邮吧?
eating noodles while reading e-mails.
你自已看!
Look for yourself!
看不 见!
It's not possible.
我认为能入侵你的电脑
To be able to hack into your computer...
又能拐着弯看着你 ...
and see you eating noodles...
坐在这儿吃拉面看电邮
and reading e-mails,
那就只有一种可能性!
there's only one possibility!
胭脂的鬼魂!
Rouge's ghost!
喂!
Hello!
如果你觉得安全  真的不会危害他人
If you think your writings are not maleficent,
为什么要隐瞒那口井?
why did you leave out details about the well?
这就是第三个错误
That's your third mistake.
你不敢说出真相!
You dare not tell the truth!
是害怕承认有胭脂的存在!
You dare not own up to Rouge's existence!
胭脂存不存在跟我有什么关系?
Rouge's existence doesn't matter to me!
你为什么要打给我?
Why do you have to call me?
你怎么会知道我号码?
How did you get my number?
当然有关系!
Of course it matters.
这代表你看到过井里的东西!
It shows you've seen what's inside the well!
喂!
Hello!
他为什么要跪拜那个石壁?
Why did he kneel in front of the cliff?
明天我们再跟次吧!
Let's tail him again tomorrow!
他肯定知道大宅在哪?
He definitely knows where the mansion is.
抱抱我好吗?
Give me a hug.
今天我不想!
I'm not in the mood today!
永远是你想就可以?
You always get what you want...
我想必须看你心情!
but I have to follow your mood!
小枫
Fanny!
小枫! 小枫!
Fanny! Fanny!
小枫!
Fanny!
霍 强! 霍 强!
John! John!
喂?  你们去哪?
Hey? Where are you?
小枫!
Fanny!
天平! 小心点!
Timmy! Be careful!
你怕什么呀?  你胆子大就行了!
Chill out! Pluck up your courage!
喂?
Hello?
我们找到荒村大宅了!
We found the mansion!
这里也没什么可怕的呀
Nothing scary here.
别 进 去 呀!
Don't go in!
啊! 你是担心我们进了大宅以后
You're afraid after we've entered the mansion,
荒村就不是你的独家秘密了吧!
The Village's secret will no longer be exclusive.
你们赶快回来!
You guys come back right away!
喂?  你大声点!
Hello? Louder, please!
喂
Hello!
霍 强
John!
你上来!
Come up here!
根据小说的描述
According to the novel,
当天胭脂的丈夫 ...
Rouge's husband was dragged...
被村民拖到东边的地下室
to the Eastern cell...
活活地被烧死!
and burned alive!
胭脂个人沐浴净身
Rouge took a bath by herself.
决定引火自焚!
She decided to set herself on fire.
最后
In the end,
她被火舌活活吞噬
she was engulfed by the fire alive...
就死在这里!
and died here!
天 平
Timmy!
瞧给你们吓的! 逗你们玩呢!
I was just kidding you guys!
无聊
Idiot!
既然我们已经来了
Since we're already here...
就证明下那个傅说!
let's verify the legend!
只有真诚相爱的人 ...
Only people truly in love...
才能受到鬼魂的祝福!
will be blessed by Rouge!
虚情假意的
The hypocritical...
神秘的力量就会出现
shall be possessed by Rouge...
把他整死!
till they die!
小枫! 你想斡什么?
Fanny! What are you trying to do?
我们要抓紧时间证明自已!
We better prove ourselves before too late!
我们可以互相提问  但是不能说谎
We can ask each other questions but cannot lie.
否则的话  胭脂的鬼魂就会上身!
Or Rouge's spirit will possess us.
能别开这个玩笑吗?
Can we stop joking?
来吧
Let's start!
好啊! 我这里有把刀
OK! Here's a knife.
这刀尖对着谁! 谁就可以向人提问!
Whoever the knife points at can ask first!
哎! 小枫!
Fanny!
春雨
Rain
你有没有做过对不起天平的事情啊?
have you ever been unfaithful to Timmy?
不是吧! 你是不是嫉妒我们呀?
No way! Are you envious of us?
算了吧! 我们还是去外面看看吧!
Forget it! Let's step outside and take a look!
没事!
Never mind!
反正我也有话要说清楚!
I got something to clarify anyway!
有科学家解释鬼魂
Some scientists believe spirits...
当人类的大脑受到电磁波的影响 ...
are illusions triggered...
而产生了幻觉
by EM waves.
有读者读你的小说而想起了胭脂
When a reader thinks of Rouge on reading your book,
这个读者的思想就产生了微弱的电磁波
his thoughts generate a weak EM wave.
不过由于你的小说粉丝丝太多
But since you have so many fans,
每个读者的电磁波 ...
their EM waves gather together...
因为共鸣而聚在了一起!
当波频和波幅越来越强的时候
When their frequency and amplitude become strong,
它就傅回到你的脑子里
they will be transmitted to your brain,
让你产生了幻觉!
giving you illusions,
让你误以为和胭脂在通电邮
making you think you e-mailed with Rouge...
跟她在讲电话!
and talked to her on the phone!
干嘛?
What?
听听
Listen!
当越来越想她的时候
The more you think of her,
幻觉会变得更立体
the more 3-dimensional the illusion becomes.
胭脂就出现在你的眼前了!
Rouge will materialize in front of you!
胭脂来 了!
Rouge is here!
神经病!
Crazy!
吓死我啦!
You scared me to death!
你吓死我啦!
It's you who scared me to death!
你来干什么啊?  改行送外卖了?
Why are you here? Are you a delivery boy now?
你管得着吗?
None of your business!
我叫他来的!
I asked him to come!
一人计短, 两人计长!
Two heads are better than one!
其实我都跟你说了,
As l told you before,
要是真的见鬼  你找我也没用
if you really see a ghost, there's nothing l can do.
我无能为力!
I'm powerless!
你多叫几个人也没用!
It doesn't matter how many people you ask!
你本性多疑  谁也不相信!
You're suspicious in nature. You don't trust anyone!
其实所有怕异的事情 ...
It depends on...
是看你用什么角度去解释
how you interpret these weird things,
重点是如何去解决!
how you go about solving them!
拿去吧!
Take it!
谢谢 啊!
Thanks!
干嘛呀?
What's the matter?
镜子! 是鬼魂现身的种媒介!
Mirror! A medium for ghosts to show up!
当电磁波转化成幻觉的初期
When EM waves first turn into an illusion,
现实环境看不见  却逃不过镜子!
it's invisible in real life but not in a mirror!
你说到镜子我就懂了
I know about mirrors.
这东西是我们他侦探反跟踪的好帮手!
We detectives use them for counter-surveillance.
你干嘛让她走啊?
Why did you let her go?
我早跟你说过了
I told you before,
对鬼我是无能为力的
I'm powerless with ghosts,
特别是这种冲着你来的冤鬼!
especially one who's targeting you for revenge!
无聊
Humbug!
平时不作亏心事  半夜不怕鬼敲门!
A quiet conscience sleeps in thunder!
一切只怕你不守承诺!
It's all because you broke a promise!
我一直都在信守承诺!
I've always kept our promise!
是 吗?
Really?
那你为什么要写荒村?
So why did you write THE VILLAGE?
那次我们去探险之后  你不是说过
After our exploration, didn't you...
荒村只是我们两个人的秘密!
say it's our secret?
谁知道你就像分手后的情侣
I didn't know you'd tell the whole world...
把一切都告诉了全世界
like a jilted lover.
还要说我的坏话!
And you even badmouthed me!
我说你什么坏话啊?
What about did I badmouth you?
荒村是我们的故事
The Village is our story.
我没有不让你写啊!
I didn't forbid you from writing about it!
你欧阳小枝大作家  你也有权去写呀!
You could write about it too, Miss Gigi Ouyang!
要不是我把荒村的典故告诉你
If l hadn't told you the legend,
你会知道吗?
would you've known?
小偷
Thief!
虽然你你是欧阳家的后人
Although you're an Ouyang,
也不代表人家不能写!
it doesn't mean others cannot write about it!
我不写  是因为你说过 :
I didn't write about it because you said...
谁都不能独自去荒村
neither of us should go there alone.
这大宅只是属于我们两个人甜蜜的回忆
The mansion is the sweet memory of us both.
可是现在你把一切都写出来
Now that you've written all about it,
就有人去找荒村了
other people will go look for the Village.
你就不怕他们破坏你的回忆
You're not afraid they would mar your memory.
对呀  你说得对! 现在真的有人去了
Sure, you're right! Someone has indeed gone there.
你说什么?
What did you say?
可是这不是我写荒村的意图!
But that wasn't my intention!
那你为什么要写?
So why did you write the book?
我们分手以后
After we broke up,
我一直在找你!
I was looking for you all the time!
只是每一次打电话给你
But every time I called you,
都转到留言信箱!
it's always voice-mail.
那你就留言呀!
You should have left a message!
谁让你永远都不会有话直说!
Why can't you be straightforward for once?
其实你只要打两次我就会接电话
If you'd called twice, I would have answered.
为什么要打两次?
Why should I have called twice?
因为你第一次打 ...
Once means...
可能是因为寂寞或者冲动
you're lonesome or impulsive;
但是你第二次打我就能确定你想我
twice means you're really missing me.
你永远就喜欢加点自以为是的规则
You always like creating your own rules.
我就是这样的呀!
That's the way I am!
打从第一天认识你  我就告诉过你
Ever since the first day l met you, I've told you...
我不是你的平衡剂
I wasn't your equalizer.
我不会照顾人  我需要别人照顾的!
I don't take care of you. You don't take care of me.
我也不会安定下来
I won't settle down...
我天天都会在制造麻烦的!
and l'm a troublemaker.
你一开始觉得我没问题的
At the beginning, you were OK with that.
你觉得 ... 你觉得你可以接受
You found...you found it acceptable.
但是后来你觉得我很讨厌!
But then you started finding me annoying.
我做什么你都讨厌!
You were annoyed at everything l did.
反正我就是很讨厌就对啦!
I'm annoying after all! That's it!
小姐
Miss
我什么都没说! 当初是你先跑的!
I hadn't said anything! You left me first!
讨厌的郭径又回来了!
The annoying Gene is back!
是讨厌的小枝又回来了!
It's the annoying Gigi who's back!
喂
Hello?
郭径吗?
Is that Gene?
我实在受不了啦!
I can't stand it anymore!
你快来 救救我!
Help me!
霍强他 ...
John, he...
霍强他们快把我逼疯了!
John and the others are driving me crazy!
你在哪里啊?
Where are you?
还在荒村啊
Still in the Village?
我刚刚还在画室
I was in the atelier.
现在却在一个公共电话亭
Now I'm inside a phone booth.
我不知道这是哪!
I don't know where l am!
那你周围有什么东西?
What're in the surroundings?
有什么建筑物吗?
Any buildings?
对不起  小枫最近经常做恶梦
Sorry, Fanny has been having nightmares lately.
不过现在己经安定下来 了
But she's calmed down already.
你叫小枫听一下!
Pass the phone to Fanny for a sec!
啊! 公车来了! 我们刚回来
Oh! The bus is here! We just came back.
现在要赶车回宿舍!
We gotta catch the bus for the dorm!
请问有人知道韩小枫在哪里吗?
Anyone knows where Fanny Han is?
你怎么会在这里啊?
Why are you here?
废话! 还不是你说你担心那四个学生
You said you're worried about those students.
我打电话给我朋友让他帮忙查一下
I called a friend to investigate for me.
今天早上给我回了个电话
He called me this morning,
说有一个女孩很像我说的那个
said he found a girl that fit my description...
不过人己经死啦!
but she's dead already!
我过来证实一下!
I came here to check it out!
我可以进去看下吗?
Can l go in and have a look?
她有三只眼睛!
She has three eyes!
小枫肯定拍到什么了!
Fanny must have photographed something!
会不会是胭脂?
Could it be Rouge?
不可能!
Impossible!
都说过你不应该写荒村!
I told you not to write about the Village!
看  现在闯祸了吧!
See, shit has hit the fan now!
痛吗?
Does it hurt?
说话啦  现在有没有觉得好一点?
You finally speak! Feeling better now?
接下来我们怎么办?
What should we do next?
报告长官  接下来我们分头行事吧!
Sir, let's take separation action!
我监视霍强  叶萧跟踪春雨
I'll watch over John, Ye over Rain...
而你就看紧苏天平!
and you over Timmy!
你先回家吧!
You go home first!
这事你不用操心  我会解决!
Don't worry. I'll take care of it!
讨厌的郭径又回来了!
The annoying Gene is back!
喂!
Hello!
我见到那口井!
I saw that well!
那天中午
That afternoon,
天平掉下来之后
after Timmy fell down,
我们都非常害怕
we were terrified.
想立刻离开
We wanted to leave right away.
可是你也知道
But as you know,
要离开
in order to leave,
就一定要等!
we first had to wait!
不等的话
Otherwise,
就不知道那里的蝙蝠有多凶!
you'd be attacked by the bats!
我们被迫困在那里
We were stuck there.
可是原本好好的四个人
The four of us used to be good friends.
却各怀心事
But we started harboring secret thoughts.
有意逃避!
We were avoiding one another!
我跟天平十五岁就认识
I met Timmy when we were fifteen...
从小到大都没有分开过
and we've been inseparable since.
可是那一刻 ...
But at that very moment...
我觉得和他在一起很有压力!
I felt a lot of pressure being with him.
你明明知道春雨喜欢装可爱
You know very well Rain is coquettish...
可是你还甘心受骗!
and you still have to fall into her trap!
你什么意思啊?
What do you mean?
你是笑我笨孩儿  看不起我?
Are you saying I'm dumb and you despise me?
我就是看不起你!
I indeed despise you!
人家给你露点肉
She only shows you some flesh...
你就跟哈巴狗一样!
and you become her dog!
小声点!
Hush!
韩小枫! 你听听你怎么骂人!
Fanny! Just listen to your vicious tongue...
就该知道霍强为什么对我朝思暮想!
and you'll understand why John lusts after me!
小枫!
Fanny!
干嘛呀?  我跟你就这么一次
Why? We've only done it once...
以后什么关系都没有!
and that's it! No more strings attached!
小枫!
Fanny!
当时只是拌了几句嘴
I was just bickering for the sake of bickering.
其实我只爱天平一个的!
In fact, l only love Timmy!
不过有哪个女生不喜欢被人家追求
But which girl doesn't like to be chased,
尤其是好朋友的男朋友
especially by her boyfriend's best friend?
谁都会觉得挺刺激的!
Every girl should feel excited!
怎么啦?
What happened?
你干什么啦?
What have you done?
没想到
I never imagined...
刺激是需要付出代价的!
there's a price for this excitement!
你把小枫推下去了!
Did you push Fanny down?
没有! 小枫刚才拉着我!
No! Fanny was pulling me!
不! 是小枫把我手甩开
No! Fanny let go of my hand...
才不小心掉下去的!
and fell down!
是你先推她的?
Did you push her first?
是她把我手甩开才不小心掉下去的!
She let go of my hand and fell down accidentally!
我问你有没有推她?
I'm asking you, did you push her?
我没有!
No, l didn't!
你说什么!
What did you say?
我不知道!
I don't know!
怎么可能不知道!
How can you not know?
我真的不知道!
I really don't know!
那你 ... 到底有没有下过那口井?
Did you...go down the well after all?
小枫!
Fanny!
你们怎么在这儿?
Why are you here?
我们刚才不是在跟郭径说话吗?
Weren't we talking to Gene?
这是什么地方啊?
What's this place?
小枫一直闹个不停
Fanny kept on babbling.
我们当时以为她受到了撞击
We thought she hit her head...
短暂失忆!
and lost her memory temporarily.
可是现在我知道
Only now do we understand...
那不是失忆
it's not memory loss.
就像傅说里说的
Like what is said in the legend,
是我们通不过爱情的测试
we didn't pass the love test.
胭脂的鬼魂己经跟来了
Rouge's spirit has followed us.
一定要把我们整死!
She wants us dead!
你别胡思乱想
Don't think too much.
胭脂是傅说!
Rouge is only a legend!
小枫的死是意外!
Fanny's death is an accident!
根本没人跟着你!
Nobody followed you.
霍强己经被胭脂缠上了
John has been possessed by Rouge.
下一个 ...
The next one...
就是我!
shall be mine!
自从韩小枫出事
After Fanny's accident,
霍强就己经搬回他老家暂住了!
John has moved back to his family home.
怎么他一走  就那么多人来找他
Why are so many people looking for him now?
刚刚还有个女孩来过!
A girl just came.
不是我推她下去的
I didn't push her down.
真的不是我推她下去的!
I really didn't push her down!
不是我 ...
It's not me...
是我
It's me!
现在情况是这样的啊!
Here's the situation:
据警察分析
according to the police report,
这又是一宗意外!
this is another accident!
不可能!
Impossible!
看你们俩默契的啊!
See how in sync you are!
还系一样的围巾!
And you're wearing the same kind of scarf!
怎么啦?  又不玩分手啦?
Well? You're no longer separated?
难道他们是真的被胭脂缠上吗?
Were they really possessed by Rouge?
你别乱想了
Stop being delusional!
你帮个忙查一下吧!
Help me investigate.
我怎么查啊?
How do I investigate?
你奇幻小说写多了?
You must have written too many detective stories.
你以为这是什么?
What do you think this is?
密室杀人案吗?
Murder in a private cell?
霍强死在一个锁着的浴室里
John died in a bathroom locked from inside.
那屋子里没有其他人!
There's nobody else there!
这个小枝知道吧
Gigi knows that.
要么是小枝撒谎
Either Gigi lied...
要么根本小枝就是凶手  对不对?
or she's the murderer herself, right?
我只是一个侦探
I'm just a detective.
我不会抓鬼!
I'm no ghost buster!
首先是韩小枫
First, it was Fanny.
接着是霍强  那?
Then, it was John. And?
春雨
Rain
行了! 我己经通知了我的警察朋友
I've already asked my police friends...
如果一有消息  他就会打给我的!
to call me if there's any news.
她刚才在地铁站想要跳车自杀
She tried to jump the tracks in a subway station.
幸好当时没有列车驶过!
Lucky there wasn't any train.
你们是谁呀?  跳车?
Who are you? Jumping the tracks?
天平呢?
Where's Timmy?
刚才还在这里吃冰淇淋呢?
Wasn't I eating ice cream here just now?
我们怕她再出什么意外
We locked her up,
所以把她给关了起来!
lest she'd have an accident.
可以进去看一下吗?
Can we go in?
春雨
Rain
你们是谁呀?
Who are you?
你们要干嘛呀?
What do you want?
你们为什么要绑着我?
Why did you tie me up?
松开我! 冷静点!
- Untie me! - Calm down!
松开我!
Untie me!
护士  镇静剂!
Nurse, Tranquillizer!
松开我! 请你们先出去!
- Untie me! - Please get out first!
松开我!
Untie me!
我们先出去  走 ...
Let's go...
我上次说过  鬼魂只是电磁波
I told you, ghosts are just EM waves.
鬼上身就很容易解释了
It's easy to explain possession.
你来!
You come here!
人类的大脑平时运动会发出beta波
Human brains normally give out Beta Waves.
手!
Hand!
可是荒村井底的电磁波冲击着大脑
The EM waves in the well bombarded their brains.
你们看  两个磁波相撞
Look, the two waves are hitting each other.
beta波乱了  不发疯才怪!
The Beta Waves are disturbed, causing mental disorder.
就那么简单吗?
That simple?
孙子楚  你能在春雨父母赶到之前
Tru, before Rain's parents arrive,
证明她是否鬼上身吗?
can you prove she's not possessed?
试试
I can try.
这个监察电磁波的仪器很敏感
This wave detector is very sensitive.
如果你们随便一拨电话  它都会有反应
Whatever you dial, it will react.
如果有信号
A signal indicates...
就证明这个房间里有神秘的物体!
there're unknown objects here.
喂
Hello
你打给我斡嘛?
Why are you calling me?
是你叫我随便打一通电话嘛?
You said I could dial whatever number.
吃饱了撑的!
You have too much time on your hands or what?
这是明朝的文物
This is an antique from the Ming Dynasty.
有驱鬼功能!
It's used for exorcism.
现代人叫照妖镜!
We call it Magic Mirror now.
你们要斡嘛?
What are you doing?
怎么又是你?
It's you again?
这是谁呀?
Who is it?
这不是我?
It's not me.
你们对我做了什么?
What have you done to me?
怎么把我变成这个样子?
Why do I look like that?
胭脂上身啦!
Possessed by Rouge?
如果她不是你
If she's not you,
那她是谁?
then who is she?
春雨
Rain
你不要怕
don't be scared.
我们是来帮你 的!
We're here to help you!
来
Come
你看  这个是我
Look, this is me.
那这个是你吗?
So that's you?
不  这个不是我!
No, this is not me!
我脸上的雀斑呢?
Where are my freckles?
怎么都不见了?
Why are they gone?
还有我的头发也不是这个样子的!
My hair isn't like that!
怎么会又短又卷呢?
How comes it's short and curly?
应该是又直又软的!
It's supposed to be straight and soft!
天平说过
Timmy told me...
他最爱看我梳羊角辫的样子
he likes me wearing ram's horn braids.
天平呢?
Where's Timmy?
他在哪里啊?
Where's he?
刚才我们还在一起啊!
We were together just now!
他给我做了我最爱吃的冰淇淋!
He made my favorite ice cream for me!
我为什么会在这里呀?
Why am I here?
我怎么知道你的仪器能不能用啊!
How did l know your equipment didn't work?
孙子  我时间不多了!
Tru, I'm out of time.
你赶快帮我准备好不好?
Do get it ready for me soon.
你要回荒村?
You're going back to the Village?
你说得对
You're right.
我不应该把荒村的事情写出来
I shouldn't have written about the Village.
我觉得我有责任!
I feel responsible!
你觉得你没有责任告诉我?
You don't think you need to tell me?
我为什么每一次都要问你的意见呢?
Why do I always have to ask your opinion?
因为你对我承诺过!
Because you promised me!
这件事情你可以不管吗?
Can you stay out of this?
你还是那么自以为是
You're still so self-centered.
只要别人跟着你走!
You want others to follow you!
我告诉你我可不是月球
I told you, I'm not the moon.
不会按照你的轨道跟着你走的!
I won't follow your path.
我懂
I know.
你永远就是太阳
You're always the sun...
我就是地球  我一定要围着你转 吗?
and l'm the Earth. I have to rotate around you?
你们好
How are you?
春雨
Rain
你是谁呀?
Who are you?
我是天平
I'm Timmy.
天平不是你这个样子的
You don't look like Timmy.
他没有黑眼圈
He doesn't have dark pouches.
头发也比你干净多了!
His hair is much cleaner than yours!
他也不会不刮胡子
And he's always clean shaven.
天平是个傻气的大男孩
Timmy is an ingenuous boy.
他没有心机
He's not cunning at all.
话也不多
He doesn't speak much.
只会傻傻地陪我!
He only likes to keep me company.
刚才 ...
A moment ago...
我还偷偷地亲了他一下
I secretly kissed him...
谁叫他每次都不主动
because he never takes the initiative.
可是他喜欢这样!
But that's the way he is!
我说过
I told you before,
我愿意做你的木偶
I'm willing to be your puppet,
陪伴你一辈子
spending my life with you.
可是我居然忘了我的承诺
Who'd expect l could have reneged.
悄悄的偷走了!
I've stolen away!
你是谁呀?
Who are you?
你怎么知道我和天平之间的事情?
How do you know about Timmy and me?
我就是天平呀!
I am Timmy!
放 开 我! 你是谁呀?
Let go of me! Who are you?
春雨! 我是天平呀?  春雨!
Rain! l'm Timmy! Rain!
春雨
Rain
这首歌 ...
This song...
是咱俩最爱唱的
is our favorite.
你第一次唱给我听
The first time you sang it to me,
是我们俩一起骑车去图书馆的时候!
we were on our way to the library!
医 生! 医 生!
Doctor! Doctor!
医 生!
Doctor!
春雨的脑细胞己经开始有死亡的迹象了
Rain's brain cells are showing signs of atrophy.
医生只能一直用药让她昏睡
Only induced...
这才能保住她性命!
coma can keep her alive!
孙子呀  你们是不是真的能找到胭脂?
Tru, can you really find Rouge?
我哪知道?
Who knows?
不管是不是真的有胭脂
Whether or not Rouge really exists,
一切都因为荒村而起
everything started with the Village.
总得去一趟
I gotta go back,
不然春雨就没救了!
or Rain will not survive!
那行吧! 我就送到这儿!
OK! l'll stop here.
你们一切多保重啊!
Take care, you guys!
多加小心啊!
Be careful!
是你不守承诺在先的  独自回荒村
If you hadn't reneged and returned to the Village,
我也不用像傻子一样跟着你吧?
I wouldn't need to follow you like a fool!
这可不是闹着玩的  小姐!
This isn't a game, Miss!
我从来都不闹着玩的
I never said it's a game.
当初是你先把荒村大宅公开的
It's you who first opened the door to the mansion.
好像是你不认真看待的吧!
Looks like you didn't take it seriously.
孙 子! 你 ...
Tru! You...
下井的人应该是我
I should be the one going down the well.
我是欧阳家的后人
I'm an Ouyang.
秘密应该由我打开!
I should find out the secret!
可以呀!
OK!
孙子  帮她穿衣服!
Tru, help her get dressed!
你先别下来!
Don't come down yet!
听他的!
Listen!
郭径  你又不守承诺  死性不改!
Gene, you've reneged again! Old habits die hard!
你不要急
Be patient.
如果下面真的有古怪
If there's really something weird down here...
我出事了
and l meet with any mishap,
能救我的人就只有你个
you're the only one who can save me.
我现在的命就交给你了
I'm giving you my life now.
你就听我一次
Just listen to me for once.
好吗?
All right?
还有
By the way,
如果你真的下来  出事了
if you come down and something happens to you,
我想我应该不能够继续生活
I don't think l can live on.
但如果换成是我
However, if something happens to me,
我想你应该可以面对
I think you can handle it.
因为你一直都比我强
You're always stronger than l.
你听到吗?
Did you hear me?
小枝?
Gigi?
喂?
Hello?
你听到吗?
Can you hear me?
谁都听到了!
Everybody can hear you!
你婆婆妈妈的  仪器快没电了
So corny! The machine will be out of battery soon.
一会出事  没人救你了!
If anything happens, nobody can save you!
设办法  你继续跟他调情吧!
What the hell, keep dallying with him.
要不然  不知道他的死活呢?
Or we won't know if he's alive or not.
郭径
Gene...
老孙又批准我们俩说话了!
Tru has given us permission to talk!
你叫他不用担心
Tell him not to worry.
这里我们比他熟!
We're more familiar with this place.
你也不能怪他
You can't blame him.
还记得两年之前我们俩来的时候
When we came here two years ago,
你也被这里的磁场给吓坏了!
you were also shocked by the magnetic field.
你还说
Look who's talking.
上次你不听我话把工具箱放下
You didn't drop the toolbox as I told you...
结果呢
and was sucked...
就像超人一样被吸上天花板去了
to the ceiling like Superman.
差点吓死我!
You almost scared me to death!
吓你个头  我还记得你说好玩呢!
Scared? l remember you said it's cool!
要是我说怕的话  你不就更怕了吗?
If l'd said l was scared, wouldn't you be more scared?
可是这里这么奇怪
This place is so weird.
当初你就应该听我的意见
You should have listened to me...
把你小说里的胭脂写成恐怖的女鬼
and turned Rouge into a scary ghost in your book.
谁让你小说里的人物都是楚楚可怜的呀
Why does she have to be a tragic figure?
这是你的东西  我不敢偷来用
That's your idea. I didn't dare to plagiarize it.
作为一个普通读者
As an ordinary reader,
我认为郭径是把胭脂当作小枝来写
I think Gene modeled Rouge on Gigi.
所以说这才叫可怕的
That's what l call scary.
那我认为呢  这位读者应该是书念少了
I think this reader must be uneducated!
胭脂跟小枝都一样可爱
Rouge is as lovable as Gigi.
怎么会可怕呢?
How can you find her scary?
对呀
TRUE
就因为这句话才叫可怕!
That's exactly what scares me!
郭径  郭径?
Gene, Gene?
郭径
Gene
是郭径吗?
Is that Gene?
你是谁?
Who are you?
你为什么会在这里?
Why are you here?
这是什么地方?
What's this place?
这本书本来是我想借的
I wanted to borrow this book.
却被你捷足先登啦!
You got it first!
你要看吗?  先借你啊!
You want it? l can lend it to you.
不用了!
No need!
口是心非呀你!
You liar!
不知道你信不信
Believe it or not,
我刚才在图书馆里面做了个梦
I had a dream in the library.
梦里看见你在一个古井旁
I saw you standing by a well,
双目通红
eyes all red.
还扑过来亲我!
You jumped at me and tried to kiss me!
真的假的?
Are you kidding?
真的!
Not at all!
你追女生的技巧也太差劲了吧?
That's the worst pick-up line I've ever heard!
还梦中情人呢! 能有点创意嘛?
A dream lover? How unoriginal!
你看侦探小说  你是探险家吗?
You read detective novels. Are you an explorer?
不是  我喜欢写奇幻小说
No, l like writing fantasy tales...
然后在网路上面发表
and publishing them on line.
所以在图书里面参考参考
I was doing research at the library.
我跟你讲  我也喜欢写小说的
Tell you what, l also like to write novels.
那你在网路上面发表文章
When you publish your writings on line,
你有笔名吗?  你是作家吗?
do you use a pen name? Are you an author?
我姓郭  单名径! 没有笔名
My name is Gene Guo. I don't use a pen name.
我也用真名的! 欧阳小枝!
Me neither! l'm Gigi Ouyang!
平常网路上的人都问我说
People on the web like to ask me...
你跟欧阳锋有什么关系?
if my name is taken from Minnelli's film.
他们还说  你是古代人吗?
Some of them ask if l'm a porn star.
我也不知道我爸妈 ...
I don't know...
为什么给我起小枝这个名字
why my parents named me Gigi.
你说小枝又没有树叶  又没有花
In Italy, Gigi is the short form for Luigi.
一枝干树枝有什么好玩的!
So Gigi can also be a man's name!
不好笑呀?
Not funny?
很冷吧?
It bombed?
我到站了啊! 走啦! 拜拜!
Here's my stop! Gotta go! Bye!
我怎么找你?
How can l find you?
你说什么?
What did you say?
我说我怎么找你?
I said, how can l find you?
图书馆! 图书馆就行!
Library! Just go to the library!
欧阳小枝!
Gigi Ouyang!
郭径  今天是那年那月?
Gene, what day is today?
07年 8 月 8 日
August 8, 2007.
干嘛?
Why?
看清楚点  现在是10年3月24!
Look! Today is March 24, 201 0!
能救我的人就只有你一个
You're the only one who can save me.
我现在的命就交给你了
I'm giving you my life now.
如果你真的下去  出事了
If you come down and something happens to you,
我想我应该不能继续生活!
I don't think l can live on.
跟春雨一样
Like Rain,
他的脑波受到井底的磁力影响
the magnetic field has affected his brain waves.
思想回到了过去
His thoughts are regressed to the past.
还好只是三年以前
But it's lucky it's only three years back.
要不然  你我都不认得!
Otherwise, he can't even recognize us!
春雨回到了十五岁
Rain is regressed to when she's 1 5 years old.
那时候她跟天平最快乐
It's when she and Timmy were the happiest.
那郭径呢  回到了跟小枝刚认识的时候
Gene is regressed to when he first met Gigi.
我总觉得这是胭脂的鬼魂搞的鬼
I still think it has to do with Rouge's spirit.
把人留在最幸福的时光里
She keeps people in their happiest moments...
一直到死!
until they die.
初恋有那么甜蜜吗?
What's so sweet about first love?
你一个宅男你当然不理解了
You're such a geek, of course you won't get it.
我告诉你  以我做侦探多年的经验
I've been a detective for years.
甜蜜是一定的!
It's sweet for sure!
等等!
Wait!
如果真有胭脂的话
If Rouge real exists,
她只会对付背叛爱情的人!
she would only harm those who betray love.
可是  如果你看了那些肉麻的纪录
But anyone who's seen his corny video record...
你还会怀疑这小子不爱小枝吗?
would never doubt his love for Gigi is true.
就算是胭脂搞错也怪不得她!
But we can't blame Rouge if she's mistaken!
这三年里面!
For the past three years...
如果我知道郭径心里在想什么
if I had known what's in Gene's head,
我就不会离开他这么久
I wouldn't have left him that long.
你们年轻人太复杂了吧!
You young folks are too complicated.
不知道并不等于不相信的
I don't know it doesn't mean I don't believe it.
如果胭脂真的存在  我愿意向她证实!
If Rouge really exists, I'm willing to prove to her!
郭径和我虽然吵吵闹闹
Although Gene always argue with me,
但是他永远都不会离开我
he will never leave me.
怎么证明?
How do you prove that?
鬼神还听你的证言?
You think ghosts care about your evidence?
更何况爱情要怎么去证明!
Anyway, how can you verify love?
怎么啦?  做梦啦?
What's the matter? Dreaming?
又梦见我啦?
Dreamed about me again?
我不只看见你
I didn't only see you...
你还说你相信我爱你
but you were saying you believed I loved you...
不会离开你!
and l wouldn't leave you.
你以为爱情这么简单吗?
You think love is that simple?
你要知道
You ought to know...
我不是你烦恼的平衡剂
I'm not an equalizer for your troubles.
我不会陪你做梦的!
I'm not gonna dream with you.
我也 ...
And I...
我也不会照顾人
I'm not gonna take care of anybody.
我也不会安定下来  我只会制造麻烦的
I won't settle down and l'm a troublemaker.
我需要别人照顾我
I need someone to take care of me.
如果 ...
If...
你不能接受这个样子的我
you can't accept me the way I am,
就请你不要跟我随便说爱
then let's not talk about love.
让我起码我有点幻想
Leave me some room for imagination.
行吗?
All right?
可以呀
OK,
我接受!
I accept!
你再说一次
Say it again.
我说没问题
I said, no problem.
我就是 ...
I...
爱这个超麻烦的欧阳小枝!
love this troublesome Gigi Ouyang!
讨厌
Annoying.
讨厌我也接受
I accept it even if it's annoying.
Ok
过来
Come here!
走啰  游泳啰!
Come, let's swim!
我不会游泳啊
I don't know how to swim!
你看我表演啦!
Let me show you.
下来  快点!
Come down. Hurry up!
我一直想自已有一个这样大的泳池
I always want a big pool of my own...
然后跟最喜欢的人游啊游啊
so l can swim with my true love...
游到筋疲力尽为止
till l'm exhausted.
你快点参加游泳班
Take swimming lessons so ...
帮我完成梦想  知道吗?
my dream can come true.
我知道韩小枫和霍强是怎么死的了
I know how Fanny and John died.
他们根本不知道什么时候会失去控制
They didn't know when they'd lose control...
然后才遇上了意外!
and then they had an accident!
那我总比他们好
I'm luckier than they are.
起码有你们看着!
At least l have you guys to watch over me.
我知道你现在的心情
I know your feelings.
我也跟你一样
I'm like you.
甚至连你  我也不认得
I can't even recognize you.
可是我知道有个人
But I know there's one person...
无论我做了什么
who will never change...
她也不会改变
whatever I do.
当我看到她突然不开心
When l see her unhappy,
我就知道
I know...
我一定是做了一些让她很伤心的事!
I must have done something that upset her.
我想跟她从新开始!
I want to start all over again with her!
可是我做不到呀!
But I cannot.
你做不到也无所谓呀!
It doesn't matter if you cannot.
我答应过你做你的木偶
I've promised you l'd be your puppet.
只要你不放弃
As long as you won't give up,
我会一辈子陪着你!
I'll spend the rest of my life with you.
这是你做的冰淇淋吗?
Did you make this ice cream?
医生! 医生!
Doctor! Doctor!
怎么回事?
What happened?
来  让一下!
Move over, please!
麻烦你们先出去!
Please get out for the moment.
让开! 让开!
Make way!
刚刚做梦了?
Were you dreaming?
做了一个恶梦!
It's a nightmare!
还是有我?
Was I there again?
应该有吧! 不太记得!
I guess so! I can't really remember!
原来我是你的恶梦啊!
So I'm your nightmare!
最近的梦很奇怪
My dreams have been very weird lately.
但又很真实!
But they seemed so real.
好像跟你说过的那个荒村古井有关
Like the well in that deserted village.
或许我们去一次  就会知道为什么!
Maybe we can go there to find out.
我不去  我怕鬼!
I'm not going. l'm afraid of ghosts!
你都听说过荒村闹鬼的
You heard the deserted village was haunted.
我虽然是欧阳家的后人
Though I'm an Ouyang,
但是我从来都没去过!
I've never been there.
那里闹鬼的  不行! 我也不准你去!
It's haunted. No way! I won't let you go either!
闹鬼好啊!
It's cool if it's haunted!
闹鬼就不用在书里面找资料了!
I can get firsthand information if it's haunted.
你干嘛?
What are you doing?
怎么啦?
What?
我害怕!
I'm scared!
没什么好怕的!
There's nothing to be scared of.
我想回去啦  我说过这里闹鬼的!
I wanna go back. This place is haunted!
你老是爱幻想!
You're always imagining things.
我真的很害怕啊
I'm really scared.
你少喝一点  别自已吓自已  好吗?
Don't drink so much. You're scaring yourself.
我就是害怕才喝
I drink because l'm scared!
你干嘛  你又觉得我讨厌是吧?
What's with you? You find me annoying again?
没有呀
Not at all.
虽然你不承认
Although you won't admit it,
但是你的嘴脸己告诉我了
your face has betrayed you.
或者有一天你可以直接点说
Perhaps one day you will tell me pointedly...
说你讨厌我  你就会骂我烦
that you're sick of me. You'll say I'm annoying
骂我喜欢把没发生的事情说死!
and l'm too cocksure about everything.
我就是喜欢把话说死的小枝
A cocksure Gigi, that's exactly whom l like.
好吗?
OK?
我告诉你啊
I'm telling you...
如果你这是骗我的
if you ever lie to me,
我永远都不会原谅你
I'll never forgive you.
小枝同志  我保证
Comrade Gigi, l promise...
我会尽我的努力去消除你的疑虑
I'll strive to eliminate your doubt.
这是我的承诺  也是我一生的任务
That's my commitment and the mission of my life.
长官  你能力那么强
Officer, if you're so powerful,
可以让世界从此停顿
can you stop the world...
把这一刻保留下来吗?
to preserve this moment?
行  我答应你
Sure. I promise you...
荒村是我们两个人的回忆
this village is the memory of us both.
谁也不能独自回来
Neither of us should come back alone...
也不能告诉别人
or tell a third person,
免得他们骚扰我们的回忆
lest our memory be disturbed.
血氧指标降到八十八  心率一百八
SATS: 88. Heart beat: 1 08.
注射 100cc 20c
1 00cc of 20c.
血正在通过主支气管  进入右上肺叶
Blood is passing from her bronchus to her right lung.
200cc 20c
200cc of 20c.
出血止不了
Can't stop the bleeding.
另一个点也在出血准备起搏器
- Another bleeding point... - Prepare the defibrillator.
一, 二  三 ...
One...two...three...
再来!  一, 二  三
Again! One...two...three...
血氧零  心率零
SATS: 0. Heart beat: 0.
死亡时间  下午点三十分
Time of death: 1 330 hours.
麻烦你出去一下
Please go outside.
你们说的对
You were right.
爱情不是游戏
Love is not a game.
不可以去测试!
It can't be tested!
我刚刚以为 ...
Just then, I thought...
我们可以从新开始
we could start all over again.
谁知被胭脂诅咒
But we have been cursed by Rouge.
全过不了七天六夜
None of us could survive 7 days.
不会吧
It can't be.
郭径从荒村回来己经四天了!
Gene's been back from the Village for 4 days.
那三天以后的早晨他就会死
In another 3 days, he'll die in the morning.
不准说
Shut up.
郭径!
Gene!
你们可不能让他再跑了  以免发生意外
Don't let him run around, or he'll have an accident.
这不单是为了他的健康
That's not only for his health...
也要为别人着想
but for the wellbeing of other people.
你会没事的
You'll be fine.
你一定会酲过来的
You will wake up for sure.
所有的一切都会过去的
Everything will pass.
乖啦!
Be good!
快点酲过来
Wake up now.
听到没有?
Can you hear me?
酲啦!
Wake up!
我睡了多久?
How long have I slept!
整天
For the whole day.
怎么啦?  孙子
What's up, Tru?
这两块玉佩是韩小枫的家人 ...
Fanny's folks found 2 jades...
在她的遗物里发现
among her remnants.
我刚做了测试!
I just ran some test on them.
这玉佩的碳份子结构十分不稳定
Their carbon composition... is very unsteady.
可以引发的磁波幅度 ...
The magnetic waves they generate...
和古井底的磁场一样
are as strong as the magnetic field inside the well.
这是胭脂的玉佩
The jades belonged to Rouge.
那他们是拿了死人的东西以后才闯的祸
They got into trouble after nabbing her stuff.
小枫的家人也认为不吉利
Fanny's folks also think they bring bad luck.
希望让我们还回去
They want us to take them back.
要是早点发现
If we'd known earlier,
郭径就不会被胭脂缠上 了
Gene wouldn't be possessed by Rouge.
自始至终  谁都没见过胭脂
Nobody has ever seen Rouge before.
所以说  谁都说得不准
So nobody can be definite about anything.
说了几百次都不改
I've said a hundred times but you never listen.
讨厌
How annoying!
讨厌! 请问谁比较讨厌呀?
Annoying? Who's more annoying?
你干嘛不睡觉?  等我啊!
Why aren't you in bed? Waiting for me?
我干嘛要等你?
Why should I wait for you?
既然有人陪你喝酒
You have your drink buddy.
你不需要回来
Why come home at all?
你说什么?
What're you saying?
郭径  你是不是一直都很讨厌我喝酒?
Gene, are you always annoyed at my drinking?
是啊
That's true.
你是不是觉得我一直喝酒深夜不回家
You think I stayed out late drinking...
是和别的男人在外面
because I was with another man...
睡觉?
having sex?
是 啊
Yes.
好 啊
All right.
从今天开始你再不用讨厌我啦  再见
From now on, no need to be annoyed anymore. Bye!
你别走!
Don't go!
怎么啦?
What's the matter?
小枝呢?
Where's Gigi?
她明天就来  你好好休息吧
She'll come tomorrow. You take a rest.
她去哪了?
Where is she?
她到底去哪了?
Where the hell is she?
我问你
I'm asking you.
她回荒村了  她说
She's going back to the Village, she said.
你疯了
Are you crazy?
你怎么可以让她回去呢?
How could you let her go?
你不可以让她靠近那口井的
You shouldn't let her go near the well!
你先听我说
Listen up,
别着急  冷静点
just calm down first.
按住! 按住!
Push him down.
放我出去!
Let me go!
孙子  你帮我好好看着她
Tru, watch out for her.
护士!
Nurse!
我尿床呀!
I wetted my bed!
护士!
Nurse!
怎么啦?
What happened?
不好意思  我尿床呀!
I'm sorry I wetted my bed!
哎! 大作家
Hey! Big Author!
昨天我看完你荒村那本书了
I finished your book, THE VlLLAGE.
写得真不错!
Very good!
够恐怖的
Very scary.
待会儿能不能帮我签个名?
Can you autograph for me later?
我女朋友是你的超级粉丝!
My girlfriend is a big fan of yours!
来人! 病人晕倒啦  病人晕倒啦!
Help! The patient has fainted!
你没事吧?
You OK?
你别跑!
Don't run!
站住
Stop!
郭径
Gene!
你别冲动! 有话好好说
Stay cool! Let's talk.
是
Yes.
我一定要回去  这是我的命
I have to go back. It's my destiny.
很危险
He's in critical condition.
是你吗?
Is that you?
胭脂
Rouge.
是胭脂吗?
Are you Rouge?
我是欧阳小枝
I'm Gigi Ouyang.
我是来还玉佩的!
I'm here to return your jade pendants.
拿走玉佩的人己经受到了惩罚
The guys who took them have been punished.
这事跟郭径没关 系
It has nothing to do with Gene.
求你别再生气了吧
Don't be mad at him.
郭径  对不起
Gene, l'm sorry.
这次我丢下你自已先跑了
I have to leave you behind and go now.
你没有丢下我
You haven't left me behind.
我也不会让你跑
And I won't let you go.
怎么啦?  累呀?
What's the matter? Tired?
追你追得累
Chasing you made me tired.
怎么一回事?  胭脂不是相信了吗?
What's the matter? Hasn't Rouge believed me?
我下去再求她!
I'll go down and beg her again!
别做任何愚蠢的事  浪费时间!
Don't do anything stupid. It's a waste of time!
你别管  我知道我是愚蠢的
Don't stop me. l know l'm stupid...
可是我有的是时间!
but all I have is time.
可是我没有!
But I don't.
其实胭脂早就己经相信我们了!
In fact, Rouge has believed us.
她不会伤害你的!
She won't hurt you!
不然你你一早就己经出事了
Or we would have met with mishap already.
现在我们唯一能做的
The only thing we can do now...
就是安安静静的 ...
is to quietly...
一起度过每分每秒
spend every single second together.
能多一秒 ...
The longer we're together,
我就多一分满足
the more satisfied I will be.
让我们 ...
Let's...
开开心心的 ...
happily...
再爱一遍
fall in love again.
可以吗?
OK?
好
OK
我刚刚做了一个梦
I just had a dream.
恶梦啊?
A nightmare?
是一个你永远都不相信的美梦!
A sweet dream you'll never believe!
你知道
Do you know...
你离开了以后
what I've done...
我都做了些什么吗?
since you left?
快点说
Tell me.
我都想知道你 ...
I wanna know how ...
你没有我的曰子自已是怎么过的?
you've been doing without me.
我都在跟踪你
I followed you.
我去偷看你学游泳
I secretly watched you swim.
还去偷看你喝酒
I secretly watched you drink.
原来全部都是女生!
Turns out they're all girls.
我打给你
I called you...
但又不敢留言
but I didn't dare to leave a message.
于是
Consequently,
我就写了这本书
I wrote this book,
希望 ...
hoping...
把我想你的那些话
to put all my thoughts about you
全都写进去!
into words.
你傻
How silly of you!
你要是早点告诉我这些
If you had told me all this sooner,
我就不会写那些电邮来吓你了
I wouldn't have scared you with e-mails.
吓我也好啊
It's good that you scared me,
要不然 ...
or...
我们也未必会遇上
we might not have met again.
那好
All right,
从今天开始  你全都要听我的!
from now on, you must follow my orders!
以后早上起床之后
After you wake up in the morning,
早餐就是要抱抱我
you gotta hug me at breakfast.
中午呢
In the afternoon,
要讲一个笑话给我听
you gotta tell me a joke.
到了晚上
In the evening,
要用三个爱我的原因做晚餐  行吗?
you gotta cook dinner with 3 reasons you love me.
不! 三个可能太多了
No! 3 is perhaps too many.
一个就够了!
One is enough!
你现在能告诉我吗?
Can you tell me now?
郭径
Gene
我经历了许多人 ...
I've gone through...
一辈子都没办法经历的事
the most incredible experiences,
包括那些刻骨铭心的爱与遗憾!
including indelible love and regrets!
我记录下来完成了这部长篇小说
I've turned them into a novel...
献给我亲爱的朋友!
which is dedicated to my dearest friends.
谢谢大家!
Thank you all!
好  我们感谢黄小枝小姐
Thank you, Miss Gigi Huang...
和我们分享了她的新书
for sharing your new book with us.
接下来的这段时间呢
Now...
我们留给在座的朋友
we have a Q&A session.
请大家提问!
Are there any questions?
这是真实的故事吗?
Is it a true story?
这个故事是虚构的
It's fictional.
灵感是我四位朋友提供的
Inspiration came from four of my friends.
也希望他们不要介意
I hope they won't mind...
我在书中把他们全部都弄死 了
I kill them all in the book.
那你为什么要写这么一个关于爱
So why did you want to write about love...
而又离别的故事呢
and farewell?
一年之前发生了一场车祸
I had a car accident one year ago.
在那之后
After that,
我就明白  何谓真正的生离死别?
I understood the true meaning of farewell...
何谓爱?
and love.
而现在的我
Right now, I...
只能用写作去表达
can only express myself in writing...
去证明我的爱
in order to prove my love.
你己经欠了我798个爱我的理由了
You owe me 798 reasons you love me.
今天是什么?
What's the reason today?
好吧! 来
All right! Come!
我们看看 ...
Let's see...
这些读者都写了什么给你
what the readers sent you.
亲爱的作者  你好
Dear Author, how are you?
很喜欢你笔下的郭径
I like your character, Gene.
觉得他的性格很真实
I find him very real.
当然了  我把你的臭脾气都写进去啦
Of course, l've injected your ill temper into him.
你发什么呆呢?
A penny for your thoughts!
你有什么梦想吗?
What's your dream?
没有
Nothing.
那好吧
All right.
从今天开始  我黄小枝就是你的梦想啦
From now on, I, Gigi Huang, will be your dream!